Let him put Mangala Sutra.
Niech założy Mangala Sutrę.
Shri Ganesha has the power to give Mangala Sutra.
Shri Ganesha ma moc dawania Mangala Sutry.
Make Me wear this one. Come along.
Załóż Mi ją. Podejdź.
Thanks.
Dziękuję.
You have the greatest right.
Masz największy przywilej.
He turned the other way round,
Odwrócił ją na drugą stronę,
it is used this way when
tak się ją nosi
there is the first year of the marriage - you see,
w pierwszym roku małżeństwa - widzicie,
thats right, that's how it is put.
właśnie tak, tak się ją nosi.
Just married women.
Tylko mężatki.
Married women have to do. Allright.
Mężatki mają to robić. Dobrze.
All the married women and then the kanya
Wszystkie mężatki, a kanya (niezamężne)
has to do something else.
mają robić coś innego.
All of you,
Wy wszystkie,
let us have two each otherwise it would be allright.
każda z was po dwie, inaczej nie wystarczy.
You can mix them up, no harm.
Możecie je pomieszać, nie szkodzi.
Wait for all the married women.
Poczekajcie, najpierw wszystkie mężatki.
You come along.
Podejdźcie.
So here we go.
No Dobrze.
I didn't bring all My ornaments...
Nie przyniosłam wszystkich moich ozdób...
That's good.
Dobrze.
May God bless you all.
Niech was wszystkie Bóg błogosławi.
Akhanda saubhagya.
Akhanda saubhagya.
This is the blessing given to all the married women
To jest błogosławieństwo dane wszystkim mężatkom,
that let your saubhagya remain all your life
żeby wasza saubhagya trwała bez przeszkód całe życie
without any obstacles.
bez żadnych przeszkód.
No obstacles in your married life should be all the time there
Żeby nie było przeszkód w waszym małżeńskim pożyciu,
till you live.
tak jak długo żyjecie.
May God bless you
Niech was Bóg błogosławi.
Now for the kumkum.
A teraz kumkum.
You people can come,
Teraz wy podejdźcie
and married girls can come!
i mężatki też niech podejdą!
Keep a little bit for everyone
Podzielcie dla każdego po trochu.
and take it round
i rozdajcie dookoła.
and they can put it on their hands and rub it.
Mogą to wetrzeć w swoje ręce.
It's good for them.
To jest dobre dla nich.
Gregoire, you read your names that you have made,
Gregoire, przeczytałeś imiona, które przygotowałeś,
where are your names?
gdzie są te imiona?
Gregoire asks "For Shri Shiva or Shri Mahakali?"
Gregoire pyta "Shri Shivy czy Shri Mahakali?"
Yes... .Shri Shiva...
Tak... Shri Shivy...
All this is for His enjoyment only, isn't it?
Wszystko to jest tylko dla Jego przyjemności , prawda?
Again!
Jeszcze raz!
Gregoire: Om Twameva Sakshat Shri Nav Jerusalemeshwara -
Gregoire: Om Twameva Sakshat Shri Nav Jerusalemeshwara
Gregoire: He is the Lord of New Jerusalem
Gregoire: On jest Panem Nowego Jeruzalem.
Gregoire: He is the Primordial Self of Shri Mataji.
Gregoire: On jest Pierwotną Istotą Shri Mataji.
Gregoire: He is fond of Sahaja yogis
Gregoire: On lubi sahaja yoginów.
So this means that He is the Beloved of the Sahaja yogis,
To oznacza, że On jest kochany przez sahaja yoginów.
Gregoire: This is another name, there is another name, Mother, for this,
Gregoire: Na określenie tego jest jeszcze inne imię, Matko,
Priya Bhakta, so Priya is first but if you put it last,
Priya Bhakta; więc Priya jest najpierw, ale jeśli umieścicie ją na końcu,
you see - Bhakta Priya means He's fond of bhaktas,
Bhakta Priya, to oznacza, że On lubi bhaktas,
you see, Bhakta Priya.
widzicie - Bhakta Priya.
But supposing you put it that She is the Beloved,
Ale powiedzmy, że powiecie, że Ona jest Ukochana,
you see because Priya, where you put it,
widzicie gdziekolwiek Priya wstawicie,
you see, then it is My name- I am the Beloved.
jest to Moje imię, bo Ja jestem Ukochana.
You can switch it - Premi would be better
Możecie to zamienić - lepiej użyć Premi -
if you put Premi then it would be all right.
- jak użyjecie Premi, to będzie dobrze.
You can put it, Priya will be - Gregoire -
Możecie tego użyć, Priya będzie - Gregoire
Sahaja Yogi Priya it's all right,
sahaja yogin Priya, to będzie w porządku,
but if you put it "Priyaa" then immediately it means
ale jeżeli powiecie "Priyaa", to natychmiast oznacza to
just the other way round because you are addressing,
coś przeciwnego, bo wtedy zwracacie się do mnie,
you are making the thing according to Me
odnosicie to do Mnie.
I become that deity, you see?
Ja staję się tym Bóstwem, widzicie?
Sanskrit is tremendous,
Sanskryt jest niesamowity,
little change here and there and makes such a thing
wystarczy mała zmiana tu i ówdzie i znaczenie bardzo się zmienia,
because every, every consonant, every vowel has a meaning,
możecie sobie wyobrazić
can you immagine every consonant and every vowel
ponieważ każda spółgłoska, każda samogłoska
has a meaning and has a mantra because it is a devanandra,
ma znaczenie i staje się mantrą, ponieważ to jest devanandra,
it is understood only by the devas,
rozumiane tylko przez Bóstwa,
devanand created by the devas,
devanand - stworzone przez Bóstwa.
so all these have such a tremendous effect when you combine
Tak więc to wszystko, jeśli połączycie ze sobą daje tak wspaniały efekt,
all these things, you see.
wszystkie te rzeczy.
Yogi: I'll read some more names for You Shri Mataji?
Yogin: Przeczytam jeszcze kilka imion, dobrze Shri Mataji?
Allright.
W porządku.
Good, beautiful, yes
Dobrze, pięknie, tak
The same form in that photograph has come up as light,
Ten sam kształt na tej fotografii pojawił się jako światło,
have you seen that?
widzieliście to?
Just like a flame, this form.
Jak płomień.
Oil, Amla, Amla oil?
Olej, Amla, Amla olej?
I saw some Khus, Gregoire,
Gregoire, widziałam Khus,
in your bathroom I saw some khus,
w twojej łazience widziałam Khus,
is khus perfiume.
perfumy Khus.
Khus.
Khus.
I saw one, it has to be "Athar",
To powinien być "Athar",
you see from India because
z Indii,
let see this one is also "Mogra"...
bo te tutaj są "Mogra"...
Here the kind of perfumes people use are very dangerous,
Tutaj perfumy, których ludzie używają są bardzo niebezpieczne,
especially this "Tabac' is coming from tobacco,
szczególnie ten "Tabac", jest robiony z tytoniu.
you see sort of people get addicted to it,
Widzicie takich ludzi, którzy są od nich uzależnieni,
because it is an addiction.
to jest uzależnienie.
Yes, this is all right, this is all right. This is hina
Tak, to jest w porządku, to jest hina.
is it written "hina' on that? "Khus, same thing..
Jest na tym napisane "Hina"? "Khus", to oznacza to samo...
Just the same. This is allright.
To samo, w porządku.
You can apply to all the sahaja yogis, this perfume khus.
Wszyscy sahaja yogini mogą używać perfum khus.
It is clearing for your vishuddhi,
One oczyszczają wasze Vishuddhi,
right vishuddhi especially.
szczególnie prawe Vishuddhi.
Though if you have hina that is the best
Ale jeśli macie Hina, to jest najlepsze,
because that clears out your right vishuddhi very much,
ponieważ to bardzo oczyszcza prawe Vishuddhi,
but this is good for people who are speedy, heated up...
ale to jest dla ludzi, którzy żyją w pośpiechu, są rozgrzani...
Let he do it when I hold the sword.
Niech on to zrobi jak będę trzymać miecz.
I will hold the sword in this hand (hindi)
Będę trzymać miecz w tej ręce...
108 Names.
108 Imion.
Have we got copies of 108 names.
Mamy kopię 108 imion.
But you can translate it.
Ale możecie to przetłumaczyć.
Yogi: It's my wife who selected it, I am innocent.
Yogin: To moja żona to wybrała, ja jestem niewinny.
You selected it but put the blame on her.
Ty wybierałeś a ją obwiniasz.
That's why the wives are there to take all the blame
Po to są żony, żeby na nie zrzucać całą winę.
Have to open it the other way round,
Musisz otworzyć to odwrotnie,
open half,
do połowy,
that's how, fold it that side
właśnie tak, wygnij to w tę stronę.
This is the way they had it at the time of Shri Krishna
Tak to właśnie robili w czasach Shri Krishny.
Take off My hair from the back and put out My hair.
Zbierzcie Moje włosy z tyłu i przełóżcie.
She's not have the modern watch...
Ona nie ma nowoczesnego zegarka...
Best combination is green, orange and yellow
Najlepsza kombinacja to zieleń, pomarańcz i żółty.
Flowers are the best above the head...
Kwiaty najlepiej dać nad głowę....
The sign of beauty is that you cannot
Znakiem piękna jest to,
tolerate any imperfection anymore.
że nie tolerujecie już żadnych niedociągnięć.
This is very beautiful so you must make everything
Ta korona jest bardzo piękna,
in relation to that, is to be done. It's done very well.
więc trzeba dopasować do niej wszystko inne, tak trzeba. Bardzo dobrze.
Try to take complete photographs.
Starajcie się robić zdjęcia całej postaci.
This I don't need!
Tego nie potrzebuję!
You can read that in a stotra words
Możesz to przeczytać słowami modlitwy
Stand, it has to go down
Postaw, to musi zwisać do dołu.
May God bless you all, give yourself a bandhan
Niech Bóg błogosławi was wszystkich, załóżcie bandhan.
Say Lord's prayer
Powiedzcie "Ojcze nasz".
Once more
Jeszcze raz